Martinus Johannes van Middelaar

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer / DevOps

Phone: +254 114055585 / +31645301717 LinkedIn: maarten-van-middelaar-640a50213

E-mail: maarten@middelaar.dev

Software engineer with over 12 years of experience in software development and operations. I have been a software architect and a developer for both frontend and backend/API. My greatest strengths are coming up with simple tailor made solutions for complex requirements and finding minute bugs in thousands of lines of code. While I love working with the latests technologies, I appreciate legacy applications and maintain them.

Experience

2021-06 - present Software Engineer and Senior Technical Mentor

The Room, ALX Africa, Kenya, Remote

- * Mentoring over **ten thousand students** to overcome both technical and personal challenges in video sessions and chat
- * Organising live coding sessions and reviewing projects in **C**, **Python**, **Javascript**, **NGINX**, **HAProxy** among others.
- * Creating tutorials and introductions for the Holberton Inc. peer learning platform
- * Create Slack bot in **NodeJS** (PostgreSQL/Memcached)

2019-04 - 2021-06 Senior full stack software engineer

SimGroep, Rotterdam, the Netherlands, Onsite & Remote

- * Implemented backend API's in PHP Symphony using ElasticSearch, Redis and MySQL using TDD
- * Developed ReactJS frontend
- * Used Design Sprints to determine initial MVP

2018-05 - 2021-09 Senior full stack software engineer

Nationale belasting Adviseurs, the Netherlands, Remote

- * Responsible for designing architecture of application for thousands of users
- * Designed and implement web interface, API and backend logic in **PHP Yii**, using **MySQL** and **Redis**
- * Create and maintain CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab
- * Setup and maintain webservers

2017-01 - present Senior backend software engineer

Tecnolux Support, Italy, Remote

- * Designed and implement backend API in PHP and Python
- * Create backend web admin interface in PHP
- * Create and maintain CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab

2015-11 - 2019-03 **Senior full stack software engineer**

<u>Tremani</u>, Delft, the Netherlands, Onsite

- * Developed in-house CMS in PHP using MySQL and Redis
- * Consult with clients on (future) improvements

2015-01 - 2015-10 Full Stack software engineer

Trix incasso, Leiden, the Netherlands, Onsite

* Developed microservices using API's and a web interface with PHP and MySQL

2013-12 - 2014-12 Web developer

<u>Studio Projectie</u>, Leiden, the Netherlands, Onsite * Developed in-house CMS in **PHP** using **MySQL**

2005 - present Freelance web developer

Digital Nomad

* Created Wordpress and other custom CMS websites* Worked on other projects, some of them listed above.

Education

2005 **Religion and Philosophy** - University of Amsterdam, NL.

2004 Mathematics, Artificial Intelligence - University Of Utrecht, NL.

2003 **Teacher Mathematics** - Hogeschool van Utrecht, the Netherlands.

2002 **Computer Science** - Hogeschool van Amsterdam, the Netherlands.

Skills

Collaborative - I'm a good listener, building capacity in all team members and aim for a shared understanding to avoid misinterpretations.

Critical Thinking - Using deduction and logic I can pinpoint and for-see possible pitfalls on any level

Creativity - While I love to implement proven methods, I think outside the box to find alternatives that suit the given situation

Agile development - I have worked using the SCRUM methodology in different teams.

Mentoring - I have guided thousands of software engineers, both as a community of SWE's and helping them on an individual level when needed

Tools and languages

PHP (Symphony, Yii)

Typescript (ReactJS, NodeJS),

Python (Django, Flask)

C

Git, Jira, CI/CD

HTML/CSS/SASS

ElasticSearch, Redis, MongoDB, MemCached

Linux [Ubuntu, Debian]

MySQL / PostgreSQL

Cloud [AWS / DigitalOcean]

Docker

Dutch: Native, English: Fluent, Swahili: basic